《闪电侠》上季回顾
Last season, on "The Flash"...
我这是怎么了
What's happening to me?
我不是唯一受影响的  是不是
I wasn't the only one affected, was I?
我们一直在寻找其他像你一样的
We've been searching for other meta-humans,
超能力者
like yourself.
不必害怕  西斯科
Don't be afraid, Cisco.
你也被影响了
You were affected, too.
很久以前
Once upon a time
你答应要嫁给我
you agreed to marry me
我是答应了
Yes, I did.
你觉得我们结婚如何
What do you say we do that?
哈里森·威尔斯就是逆闪电
Harrison Wells is the Reverse-Flash.
是你杀了我妈妈
You killed my mother!
为什么
Why?
我们是敌人  死对头  对立面
We're enemies, rivals, opposites,
对方的反面
reverses of one another.
只要告诉警察你的所作所为
Just tell the police what you did.
让我爸爸沉冤昭雪
Get my dad out of prison!
你可以回去救你的母亲
You could go back and save your mother.
一个虫洞
A wormhole.
会产生一条连通时间本身的通道
Opening a gateway into time itself.
虫洞状态  稳定
赢的总是我  闪电侠
I always win, Flash.
艾迪
Eddie!
艾迪是他的先人
Eddie's his ancestor.
如果艾迪死了  他就不会出生
If Eddie dies, he'll never be born, and...
他的存在正在被抹除
he's being erased from existence.
虫洞状态  不稳定
奇点不会消失
The singularity won't stop,
即使整个地球都不存在了
Not even after the earth is gone.
我们得破坏它的动能
We have to disrupt the motion.
没人能阻止它
It cannot be stopped!
我必须得试试
I have to try.
-他回来了  -没错  来送死
- He's coming back around! - Yeah, to die!
我发誓总有一天我会杀了你
I swear one of these days I will kill you!
我又来晚了  是吧
I was late again, wasn't I?
时机正好
Right on time.
一次搞定两个
Two down at the same time?
超级英雄双杀  宝贝
Superhero double play, baby!
不只是我一人
Didn't do it alone.
你永远不是一个人  巴里
You're never alone, Barry.
你也一样  雷蒙德小姐
Neither are you, Mrs. Raymond.
谢谢你不在我还在你体内时
Thank you for not doing that
做这种事
when I was inside you.
就发生过那么一次  别纠结了
It happened one time. Let it go.
史纳特和罗里
Snart and Rory.
你都让我这警察没事干了
You're gonna put a cop like me out of a job.
只是尽力帮忙而已
Just trying to help.
你所做的不仅仅是帮助  巴里
You do more than help, Barry.
你给了这城市中所有人希望
You give the people of this city hope.
你是个英雄  巴里
You're the hero, Barry.
恭喜每个人
Congratulations, everyone.
一场美妙的胜利
A spectacular victory.
甚至可以说是里程碑式的
A milestone, if you will.
艾伦先生  我想我已经没什么可教你的了
Mr. Allen, I believe there's nothing left I can teach you.
我相信...
I believe...
你已经准备好单打独斗了
That you're ready to do all of this on your own.
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
巴塞罗缪·亨利·艾伦先生
紧急信件
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible,
于是我成为了闪电侠
and I became the Flash.
我用我的能力去寻找那个
I used my powers to find the man
杀死了我母亲的人
responsible for my mother's death.
我以为我最终能为我的家人带来正义
I thought I would finally get justice for my family,
但我失败了
but I failed.
距离奇点事件已经过去六个月了
It's been six months since the singularity.
我现在自己单干了  我觉得这样比较好
I'm on my own now. Decided it's better that way.
可以保护我所在乎的人
Keeps the people I care about safe.
现在我能做的只剩一件事
There's only one thing I can do now.
闪电侠之日
奔跑
I run.
辐射性
怎么样了
How's it going?
挺好的
Good.
你怎么样
How you doing?
挺好的
Good.
这个受害者  他名叫阿尔·罗斯坦
So, the victim. His name is Al Rothstein.
他是这个核电站的焊工
He's a welder here at the nuclear plant.
同事在今早发现了他
Co-worker found him this morning.
那么  你发现了些什么
So, what do you got?
脸上有瘀点  眼中发白
Petechiae on his face and the whites of his eyes,
还有他脖子周围的瘀伤
and this bruising around his neck...
这么说他是被掐死的了
Oh, so he was strangled.
被一位非常强壮非常巨大的人掐死的
By someone very strong and very large.
或是某只
Or something?
这不是古鲁德做的
This wasn't Grodd.
感谢老天爷
Oh, thank God.
这样吧
Look,
我找到更多线索后
I'll let you know
再告诉你
when I find more.
那这个闪电侠之日的事
So this Flash day thing.
我希望你能出场亮亮相
I'm hoping you're planning on making an appearance.
我还没决定呢
Ah... I haven't decided.
小巴  我听说市长准备
Bar, I heard the mayor's trying
授予你这座城市的钥匙呢
to give you the key to the city.
我不需要什么奖杯
Yeah, I don't need an award.
你多喜欢得奖
You love getting awards.
看看你在高中时拿的那些科学赛奖杯
Like all those science trophies you got in high school?
那些是我应得的
Those I deserved.
我发现了什么再告诉你  好吧
I'll let you know what I find, all right?
好的
All right.
闪电侠之日马上就要到了
Flash day is almost here.
一场位于市中心的特殊集会
A special downtown rally
来歌颂拯救了中城的那个人
to honor the man who saved Central City.
六个月前  闪电侠拯救了中城
It's been six months since the Flash saved Central City
击败了突然出现在天空中的黑洞
from the freak black hole that erupted in the sky.
乔  那个核电厂谋杀案什么进度了
Joe, where are we at with the murder at the nuclear plant?
巴里还在分析证物
Barry's still analyzing the evidence,
但肯定有点不对劲
But there was definitely something weird.
是的  所以我才让你调用
Yeah, which is why I let you have
反超能力者特别行动小组
that anti-meta-human task force.
说到这里  你的科学顾问哪里去了
Speaking of which, where's your scientific advisor?
吼吼吼
Ho, ho, ho!
膜拜大胡子
Fear the beard!
看上去非常与众不同  先生
It's a very distinguished look...Sir.
-这些是什么  拉蒙先生  -这个吗
- What is all this, Mr. Ramon? - Oh, this right here?
这是一个我正在研发的东西
This is a little something I'm working on.
这是我为乔
I'm cooking it up for Joe
和特别行动小组设计用来打倒超能力者的
and the task force to take down meta-humans.
我准备叫它靴子
I'm think I'm going to call it the boot.
收据给你
Oh, here are the receipts.
队长  还有件事
Oh, um, Captain, one more thing.
你是拿不到警徽的  拉蒙先生
You are not getting a badge, Mr. Ramon.
他对于警徽真是小气得要命啊
He's really stingy with those badges, isn't he?
警察在这方面就是这么好笑
Yeah, cops are funny that way.
你觉得你能弄好这东西吗
So you really think you can get this to work?
可别让我在大庭广众下出糗
Don't have me caught out on the streets with my pants down.
好  一旦我把靴子搞定
Yes, once I finish the boot,
中城警局就会有能够打倒超能力者的武器了
CCPD will totally have what it needs to take down a meta-human.
尤其眼下巴里已经决定走
Especially now that Barry has decided to go all
《独行侠野狼》路线  自己打击犯罪
Lone Wolf Mcquade and fight crime by himself.
可不是吗  你跟他聊过了吗
I know, right? Have you spoken to him?
没有  凯特琳开始在水星实验室工作后
Not really. Haven't even heard from Caitlin
我甚至都没跟她联系过
Since she started work at Mercury Labs.
-西斯科  爸爸  -宝贝
- Hey Cisco. Hi, dad. - Hey, baby.
你有没有和巴里说过集会的事情
Hey, I was wondering if you'd talked to Barry about the rally.
我们正说到这儿呢
We was just saying.
抱歉  不过我不敢相信
I'm sorry, but, I can't believe
他们要把城市钥匙授予闪电侠
they're gonna give the Flash the key to the city.
尽管严格意义上来说  作为闪电侠小组的成员
Although technically, as members of team Flash,
我们都应该得到钥匙
We should all be getting keys.
你知道巴里的
Well, you know Barry.
我们越劝他去做什么事
The more we try to convince him to do something,
他就越不想去做
The less he's gonna want to do it.
但他还是应该去
Yeah, but he should go.
得有个人试着劝服他
Someone should try and get through to him.
或许他最好的朋友可以去
Maybe his best friend.
乔  相信我  我试过了
Joe, believe me, I've tried.
我是说她
I meant her.
拜拜  宝贝
Bye, baby.
-好的  -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
警告
修理工作区域
若非授权禁止入内
吉特斯咖啡厅
你知道吗  如果你决定
You know, if you ever decided
不再当闪电侠了
that you didn't want to be the Flash,
做个工头也会不错
You have a good future being a contractor.
谢谢
Thanks.
我只是想要把这一切
Yeah, I'm just trying to put it all back
按照原来的摆放...
exactly how it was before the--
你知道的
You know.
看起来很多当地商铺
Seems like a lot of local businesses
都一夜之间被修好了
are being rebuilt at night.
神不知鬼不觉的
In secret.
我在考虑给报纸写篇关于闪电侠的报道
I was thinking about writing an article about it for the paper.
别  拜托了
Don't. Please.
大家都听过相关故事
Look, people have heard the stories.
也看过相关报道
They've read the articles.
甚至可能亲眼见过红衣侠从身边一闪而过
They've maybe even seen the red streak racing past them.
但他们从未见过闪电侠本人  巴里
But they've never seen the Flash, Barry.
这就是你来这里的原因吗
So that's why you're here?
过来说服我去参加集会
You came to talk me into going to the rally?
我是不会去的
'cause I'm--I'm not gonna go.
大家只是想对拯救中城的英雄致予谢意
People just want to thank the man who saved Central City.
那不行  因为不是我救的
Well, they can't, 'cause that's not me.
你应该比任何人都清楚
You should know that, better than anyone.
闪电侠之日
中城信赖闪电侠
Central City believes in the Flash.
我也是
So do I.
吉特斯咖啡厅
漂亮
Brilliant!
他在抑制奇点
He's contained the singularity
通过增加它角动量的方式
by adding to its angular momentum!!
巴里  奇点稳定了
Barry, it's stabilizing.
继续保持你现在的状态
Keep doing what you're doing!
我不确定我还能坚持多久
I'm not sure how much longer I can.
-西斯科  -现在怎么办
- Cisco! - Now what?
我们得融合内外视界
We have to merge the inner and outer event horizons.
我们该怎么做
How do we do that?
在黑洞中心分离
By separating in the eye of it.
分裂产生的巨大能量应该可以办到
The amount of energy from the fissure should do the trick.
这是我们唯一的希望了  罗纳德
It's our only hope, Ronald.
罗尼  别  太危险了
Ronnie, no! It's too dangerous.
万一能量涌入的时候你逃不出怎么办
What if you can't escape the inrush?
凯特  我们得试试
Cait, we have to try.
罗尼  教授
Ronnie... Professor...
不
No!
罗纳德   罗纳德
Ronald... Ronald...
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
闪电侠之日
你预感会有麻烦出现吗
Are we expecting trouble?
警察总是预感会有麻烦出现
Cops always expect trouble.
在这个城市  我预感是超级恶棍飞天怪物
In this city, I expect super evil flying monsters.
这预期非常精准
That's a solid expectation.
我的天呐
Well, I'll be.
早上好 中城
Good morning, Central City!
一年前  我们的世界改变了
A year ago, our world changed.
我们的城市变成了一些...
Our city became ground zero for...
诡异事情的源起地
Some pretty weird stuff.
我们这里出现一种新型罪犯
We got a new breed of criminal:
这些人不仅无视法律
Men and women who defied not only our laws,
还无视物理和逻辑
but physics and reason.
但我们也迎来了别的
But we got something else, too.
我们有了闪电侠
We got the Flash!
我们伤痕累累
Our wounds run deep,
我知道你们中很多人恐惧
And I know many of you are afraid
明天可能发生的威胁
of what threats tomorrow may bring.
但闪电侠不仅仅是保护我们
But the Flash doesn't just protect us,
他重拾了我们失去的希望
he restores hope where it was lost.
所以我很荣幸将钥匙授予
That's why I'm honored to present the key
给拯救中城的英雄  闪电侠
to the man who saved central city: The flash!
闪电侠  闪电侠
Flash. Flash.
中城的大门
The doors to central city
将永远为你敞开  闪电侠
Will forever be open for you, flash.
小心
Look out!
您没事吧
You all right?
交给我  放心吧
I got this, all right?
拯救中城的英雄
The man who saved central city.
抱歉搅了你的大典
Hate to rain on your parade.
西斯科
Cisco!
-那个靴子  -哦对
- The boot! - Right!
弹药充足上膛完毕  去吧
Locked and loaded. Go!
击中
Booted!
西斯科  你说过这东西能拿下他
Cisco, you said this thing would take him down.
他不但没倒下
He's not going down.
还变大了
He went up.
快跑
Run! Run!
-你要干什么  -我扔  你开枪打
- What are you doing? - I'm throwing, you're shooting.
他是阿尔·罗斯坦
That's Al Rothstein.
我们在核电站发现的那具尸体
The body we found at the nuclear plant,
他还活着
he's alive!
据验尸官办公室说
According to the coroner's office,
阿尔·罗斯坦的尸体整夜都在停尸房
Al Rothstein's body was in the morgue all night.
因此我们可以排除僵尸袭击了
So we can scratch off "Zombie attack."
罗斯坦有双胞胎兄弟吗
Rothstein have a twin brother?
没有  独生子
Nope. Only child.
还有这个  粒子加速器爆炸那晚
And get this, the night the accelerator exploded,
罗斯坦正在夏威夷度蜜月
Rothstein was on his honeymoon, in Hawaii.
也就是说我们要找的这个人  非常强壮
Huh. So we're looking for a guy who's really strong,
能变大两倍  并且长得恰好
can grow twice his size, and just happens to look
和自己杀掉的人一模一样
exactly like the guy he murdered?
要不是他这一切把我吓坏了
I would think this meta was really cool,
我可能会觉得这超能力挺酷的
if everything about him didn't just terrify me to my core.
就因为这个吗
Is that what happened to you?
刚才有那么一会儿你看起来真是吓坏了
You looked really spooked there for a minute.
此刻我已经看到可以询问的人了
I actually see the guy that I can ask about it right now.
回头打给你  好吧
Call you back, okay?
闪电侠之日集会旁边的医院里
So, the hospital next to the flash day rally,
X光和CT机同时失效了
The x-ray and ct machines all failed at once.
是因为你么
Was that because of you?
我没做任何可以导致这样的事情
I did not do anything that would cause that.
我可以百分之九十二确定
I'm 92% sure.
我要去百分之百确定下  借过一下
I'm going to go make that 100. Excuse me.
你还好吧
You okay?
-我们得谈谈  -好吧
- We need to talk. - Okay.
不能再让巴里自己这么干了
Barry can't do this alone anymore.
这是他的计划并且我也不知道如何说服他
That's his plan and I don't know how to talk him out of it.
这节骨眼上  我只是在努力
At this point, I'm just trying
不把他推得更远
not to push him farther away.
也许巴里能这么成功的疏远
Well, maybe Barry has been so successful
你我和其他人所有人
At pushing you, me and everyone else away,
是因为我们一直放任他
because we keep letting him.
我们不要再放任他了
Let's not let him.
你有什么办法
What do you suggest?
好吧  "如果回答一直是否定的
Well, "If you keep getting 'no' for an answer,
那就不要再问了"
stop asking questions."
这是我说的  你在引用我说的话
I say that. You quoting me to me?
不然呢  你是个很聪明的人
What can I say? You are a very smart man.
水星实验室里面原来是这个样子
So this is what it looks like inside Mercury Labs.
这里的安保比尖端科技研究实验室好太多
Security here is way better than it was at S.T.A.R. Labs,
表层控制室一直有人随便进进出出的
what with people walking in and out of the cortex all the time.
-你好  西斯科  -天啊
- Hi cisco. - Sweet sarek.
那是6K质子连接器吗
Is that a 6k proton splicer?
是的
Yes, it is.
麦吉博士坚持要求所有设备都是最新技术
Dr. Mcgee insists on having all the latest technology.
你应得的
You deserve it.
今天集会的时候我看到你了
I spotted you, at the rally today,
我猜你也看到发生了什么吧
and I'm guessing you saw what happened.
西斯科  我不会回去的
Cisco, I can't come back.
好吧  看看这个  我们在核电站
Okay, check this out: We found this on a victim
一名受害者身上发现了这个
at the nuclear power plant,
但这徽章什么都侦测不出来
But the badge shows absolutely nothing at all,
特别奇怪
which is so weird.
同样奇怪的是那个超能力者变大的同时
What's also weird is that at the same time that meta-human grew,
一英里半径范围内所有X光机都失效了
all the x-ray machines within a mile radius just went belly-up.
-西斯科  -你能不能就...
- Cisco. - Just--if you could just...
看一看这徽章有什么变化
see if the badge was tampered with or something.
它是损坏了  还是...
I mean, if it's broken, or...
别的什么情况
Whatever.
都会很有帮助的
It'll really help.
中城警局
闪电侠大败
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen.
巴里·艾伦
Barry allen?
-是我  -我是格雷格·特克
- Yeah. - I'm Greg Turk.
我是威瑟斯比与斯通律师事务所的律师
I'm an attorney at weathersby and stone.
我一般不会上门服务  但是几个月来
I don't usually make house calls, but I've been trying
我一直在尝试跟你取得联系
to get in touch with you for several months.
好吧  很抱歉
Yes. Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
我只是...
I've just, um--
警察局这边工作一直很忙
I've been really busy with police work.
我们需要谈谈尖端科技研究实验室
We need to talk about S.T.A.R. Labs.
如你所知  哈里森·威尔斯将它留给了你
As you know, Harrison Wells left the property to you
作为他生前信托的一部分
as part of his living trust.
是的  我没有要求他这样做
Yeah, which I did not ask him to do,
但我一直在保管着那里
but I've been keeping the place up.
恐怕想要保留它可不能只靠
Well, it's going to take more than cleaning the floors
擦擦地什么的
to retain it, I'm afraid.
设备和不动产按照计划将于本周末
The facility and the real estate are scheduled to go
进入破产接收程序  除非...
into receivership at the end of this week unless...
你看了这个
You watch this.
这是什么
What is this?
威尔斯博士留下的视频信息
A video message drafted by Dr. Wells.
内容是什么  你看过了吗
What's on it? Have you seen it?
没有  他强调过
No. He was very specific.
只有你能看
It was only to be watched by you.
你看过之后  这个设备会给我发送通知
The device will send me a notification after you've viewed it.
那时候  一切都准备就绪以待执行
And at that point, I'll have everything ready to execute.
我不会看的
I'm not going to watch that.
您自己决定  艾伦先生
Well, that's up to you, Mr. Allen.
我只负责传达哈里森·威尔斯最后的要求
I'm only here to represent Harrison Wells' final request.
祝安
Good day.
尖端科研实验室
你们在这干嘛呢
What are you guys doing here?
-工作  -所以凯特琳是对的
- Working. - So, Caitlin was right.
对  每个人体内都有微量辐射
Yes, all humans contain small amounts of radiation
因为平时会使用手机  微波炉
due to contact with cell phones, microwaves,
电视之类的东西
televisions, et cetera.
我们的身体本身就是导体
Our bodies are natural conductors.
我想这个超能力者吸收了周围的辐射
I think our meta's been sucking up all the radiation
来给自己供能
around him and using it to power himself.
所以医院里的X光机才会
Which is why the x-ray machines at the hospital
在集会那天无法正常运作
failed the day of the rally.
所以要想找到他
So if we want to find him,
就要查没有辐射的地段
we gotta look for places without radiation.
好了各位  现在我不希望你们在这里出现
All right, guys, I don't want any of you here right now.
硬汉  你需要搭档  需要朋友
Tough. You need your partners. You need your friends.
巴里  这里每个人都很关心你
Barry, everyone in this room cares about you,
也很关心这座城市
but we also care about this city.
我们希望城市变得更好
We all want to make a difference,
所以要去与超能力者抗争
and that means fighting meta-humans,
所以要和闪电侠合作
and that means working with the Flash.
你不能拒绝我们
You can't deny us that.
-别再拒绝我们  -发现他了
- Not anymore. - Got him.
危险废物回收厂旁边
There's a three block dead zone
三个街区成了死区
near a hazardous waste reclamation plant.
本该有大量辐射
It should be blooming with rads,
但现在辐射是零
and right now it's at zero.
在那里你就能找到这个原子粉碎者
That's where you'll find your atom smasher.
因为他吸收原子能
Because he absorbs atomic power,
然后他...粉碎原子
and he, well, smashes.
抱抱
Come here.
这个名字真酷炫  欢迎加入命名小分队
That's a great name. Welcome to the team.
-谢谢  -好极了  伙计们  谢谢你们
- Thank you. - Great, guys, thank you.
你们可以离开了
You can go now, all right?
巴里  你需要西斯科  斯泰因
Barry, you need to let Cisco and Stein
帮你想办法阻止那家伙
figure out a way to stop this guy.
不  我不需要
No, I don't.
巴里没带语音交流设备
Barry left his comm system behind.
我们没法跟他说话了
We can't talk to him.
他要孤军奋战
He's on his own.
真是出其不意
Well, this is a curve ball.
我还以为我得去找你
I thought I was going to have to come looking for you.
我不会让你再伤害任何人了
I'm not gonna let you hurt anyone else.
我只想伤害你  伙计
I'm only here to hurt you, buddy.
是吗
Yeah?
那为什么要杀阿尔伯特·罗斯坦
Then why'd you kill Albert Rothstein?
你又为什么跟他长得那么像
And why do you look like him?
我说了你也不信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
说来听听
Try me.
正有此意
I'm about to.
是不是真的没办法知道
Is there really no way of knowing
那里发生什么事
what's going on in there?
我在找那里的监控
I'm looking for the security cameras.
有啦
Booyah.
轮到我了
My turn.
爸爸
Dad.
或许我能赶过去
Maybe I can make it there.
不  你不要去
No, you won't,
就算你去了又能做什么
and what are you gonna do when you get there?
靴子对他没有用
The boot didn't work on him.
警报
Alarm!
相信我  我们已经很惊慌了
Believe me, we're all alarmed.
不  我说警报系统
No, the alarm system.
你进了监控系统对不对
You've tapped into the surveillance cameras, correct?
对耶
Correct!
来吧  感受警报声吧
Come on, feel the noize.
他还说你是什么大英雄
He said you were some kind of big hero,
不过我看你配不上他  也配不上这座城市
but you don't seem worthy of him, or this city.
斯坦因教授  您真是天才
Professor Stein, you are a genius.
我相信这是公认的
I believe that's already been well established.
不用  谢谢
No, thank you.
爱瑞丝说奶酪通心粉是你的最爱
Iris says mac and cheese is your favorite.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
已经过去六个月了  巴里
It's been six months, Barry.
你得吃点东西  孩子
You gotta eat, son.
这办法挺好
It's a good move,
一直气呼呼的
being angry all the time.
我明白
I get it.
你很想念爸爸妈妈
You miss your mom and dad,
你想证明自己变得坚强了
and you want to show them that you're strong.
生气很简单
Being mad makes it easier.
难的是释放自己的感受
Tougher thing to do would be to let yourself feel.
伤心没有什么不对  你可以伤心的  巴里
It's okay to be sad. You can be sad, Barry.
如果你不是一直那么坚强
Your parents will understand
你爸爸妈妈都会理解你的
if you're not strong all the time.
所以才需要我嘛
That is why I'm here.
没事的  孩子  有我呢
It's okay, son. I got you.
你没事了  有我呢
You're good. I got you.
大家都去哪儿了
Where is everyone?
我想你没准备好之前不想见任何人
I figured you wouldn't want an audience when you came to.
对  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
爱瑞丝说得对
Iris is right.
你不能再一个人死撑了
You're not gonna do this anymore.
过去六个月里我给你足够的空间
For the last six months I've given you your space
去消化这整件事  再回到我们身边
to work all this out, come back to us.
但今天的事证明  你宁死不愿别人帮忙
But today proved that you'd rather just get yourself killed.
我死总好过害死自己的朋友
It's better than getting my friends killed.
你要我告诉你那不是你的错吗
You want me to tell you that it wasn't your fault?
我不会的  你确实有错  但你知道吗
I can't. It was. Guess what?
那天你不是唯一一个在做决定的人
You weren't the only person making decisions that day.
我们所有人都有在做决定
All of the rest of us were there too.
艾迪和罗尼
Eddie and Ronnie,
他们选择了去帮你阻止威尔斯
they chose to help you stop Wells,
还有那个...
and stop that--
-奇点  -那个奇点
- Singularity. - Singularity thing.
那件事我们人人有份  巴里
It's on all of us, Barry.
所以别再独自承受愧疚和遗憾
So stop with this hogging all the blame and regret.
我们一起去面对
We gotta live with it.
好好生活下去
Move on.
我现在该怎么做
What do I do now?
我知道你一直...
Well, I know that you've been
在夜间努力重建中城
rebuilding Central City at night.
那只是砖瓦和油漆罢了
It's just bricks and paint.
也许你应该试着重建...
Maybe you should start trying to rebuild...
那些真正重要的东西
things that really matter.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
抱歉  我应该事先打个电话之类的
Sorry, I should've called or something.
我只是...想来看看你
I just--I wanted to see you.
有一阵子没见了
It's been a while.
是啊  西斯科说他在
Yeah, Cisco said that he saw you
闪电侠之日庆典上见到你了
at The Flash Day celebration.
我很惊讶
I was surprised.
你比任何人都清楚
You, better than anyone,
我不是那天拯救城市的英雄
know I wasn't the hero that day.
-你当然是  -不是
- Of course you were. - No.
凯特  罗尼为救我牺牲了
Cait, Ronnie died saving me.
我该救出他的
And I should've saved him,
我...我很抱歉
and I'm--I'm so sorry.
巴里  我知道你已经尽最大努力了
Barry, I know that you did everything you could.
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
罗尼的死我不怪你
I don't blame you for Ronnie's death.
我怪我自己
I blame myself.
为什么
Why?
罗尼一开始变成烈焰风暴时
When Ronnie first became Firestorm,
他问我要不要离开中城
he asked me to leave Central City,
去别处过寻常人的生活
and go somewhere that we could have a normal life.
可我拒绝了他
And I said no.
我放不下尖端科研实验室
I couldn't leave S.T.A.R. Labs,
威尔斯博士...还有你
Dr. Wells...You.
如果我当初和他走  罗尼现在也不会死
If I had gone with him, Ronnie would still be alive.
留在尖端科研实验室只会让我不停地
Being at S.T.A.R. Labs just made me think of that
想起这件事
every single day.
给你
Here.
你还随身带着手帕吗
Oh, you carry a handkerchief now?
你是80岁老爷爷吗
What are you, 80?
这是什么
What's that?
这是...
Ah, it's uh...
这是威尔斯以防不测
Apparently, in case of his death,
留下的生前遗嘱之类的东西
Wells had some kind of a living will.
你还没打开看过吗
And you haven't watched it yet?
没  没有  我...
No. No, I've...
一直太害怕
been too afraid.
那我们一起看如何
What if we watched it together?
好吧
All right.
你好  巴里
Hello, Barry.
如果你在观看这段影像
If you're watching this,
意味着事情进展得相当不尽人意
that means something has gone horribly wrong.
我死了  过去15年的努力白费了
I'm dead and the last 15 years have been for nothing.
真可惜  15年啊
Bummer. 15 years.
我意识到这些年我一直在
You know, when I realize that in all those years
帮你成长
helping raise you,
我们并不是真正的敌人  巴里
we were never truly enemies, Barry.
我不是你该记恨的
I'm not the thing you hate.
既然如此  我想把你最需要的东西给你
And so, I want to give you the thing that you want most.
也不要紧的
It won't matter.
你永远不会真正快乐  巴里·艾伦相信我
You'll never be truly happy, Barry Allen, trust me.
我了解你
I know you.
现在...
Now...
删除我在此之前说的那些
erase everything I said up to this point.
把接下来这段话交给警方
Give the following message to the police.
我叫哈里森·威尔斯
My name is Harrison Wells.
身体健康  心智健全
Being of sound mind and body,
我自愿承认谋杀了诺拉·艾伦
I freely confess to the murder of Nora Allen.
2000年3月18日晚  在其家中
In her home, on the night of March 18th, in the year 2000.
我对诺拉·艾伦进行了袭击
I attacked Nora Allen--
-我的天啊  -我刺入她的胸膛
- Oh, my god. - I stabbed her in the chest
-用一把...  -他自首了
- with a large butcher knife-- - He confessed.
在厨房水槽左侧抽屉中找到的菜刀
From the drawer to the left of the sink in the kitchen.
就是这个
This is it.
这就是释放我爸爸的证据
This is what I need to free my dad.
乔  是我
Hey, Joe. Yeah, hey.
能集合所有人到尖端科研实验室见我吗
Can you have everybody meet me at S.T.A.R. Labs?
对  好的  谢谢
Yeah. All right, thanks.
好的  再见
Yeah. All right, bye.
我来开车
I'll drive.
好的
Okay.
你觉得那段视频足够了吗
You think the video's enough?
好的  没问题
Well, sure.
-她怎么说  -等一下
- What's she saying? - Hold on.
威尔斯给出了所有匹配的细节
Wells gave all the right details.
还没最终决定  但地检官说形势喜人
It's not a done deal yet, but the D.A. says it looks good.
是的  我在
Yeah, I'm here.
是好消息吗
Is it good news?
我想是的
I think so.
亨利要回来了吗
Henry's coming home?
好吧
Okay, well...
还剩下原子粉碎者要对付呢
that still leaves Atom Smasher to deal with.
上次你和他对抗  情况不是很顺利
Last time you faced him, it did not go well.
是的  并不顺利
No, it did not.
显然我没法自己阻止他
I clearly can't stop him by myself.
所以我们要如何打败他
So how are we gonna beat him?
自从我看到了那个辐射耗尽标识
Well, ever since I was shown a drained radiation tag,
我就没办法不去想它
which I haven't been able to stop thinking about.
-托你的福  西斯科  -不用谢  凯特琳
- Thank you, Cisco. - You're welcome, Caitlin.
如果这家伙这么喜欢辐射
If this guy likes radiation so much,
不如就让他如愿以偿
I say we give it to him.
好戏开始了
Showtime.
还好吗
What's up?
看来你收到我的消息了
I see you got my message.
那个灯是完美的诱饵
That light was perfect bait.
你是怎么想到的
What made you think of that?
不知道  应该是在漫画书里看到的
I don't know, I think I saw it in a comic book somewhere.
你要抓我
You want me?
你必须先跟上我
You're gonna have to catch me.
闪电侠
罗斯坦
成功了  伙计  罗斯坦在跟着你呢
It's working, dude. Rothstein's following you.
不得不说  他这样的体形还挺灵巧的
I must say, he's quite agile for a man his size.
跑  巴里  快跑
Run, Barry, run.
快啊
Come on.
以为我抓不到你吗
Didn't think I could catch you, huh?
不  我知道你能
No, I knew you could.
就是现在  西斯科
Now, Cisco!
反应堆芯 已激活
那个房间涌出的辐射量...
The amount of radiation about to flood that room--
原子粉碎者无法完全吸收
Atom smasher won't be able to absorb it all.
反应堆芯         正在冷却
反应堆芯         已冷却
辐射清除了
The radiation's been cleared.
你可以安全进入了
It's safe for you to go in.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不能再让你伤害任何人
I couldn't let you hurt anyone else.
为什么
Why?
你为什么想杀我
Why did you want to kill me?
如果我杀了你
He promised he'd take me home...
他答应带我回家
if I killed you.
谁
Who?
谁答应过你
Who promised you that?
极速
Zoom.
铁山监狱
离开这里吧
Let's get out of here.
来赛个跑
I'll race you.
铁山监狱
你会输的
You will lose.
欢迎回家
Welcome home!
判决被推翻
亨利·艾伦
获得释放
欢迎回家
亨利
大家请过来一下
Gather round, everyone, please.
看着你们
Looking at all of you,
想想我们经历的这些事
thinking how far we've all come,
回忆那些已不在我们身边的人
and remembering those who are no longer with us,
使我想起了一个
I'm reminded of a hebrew word
欢迎回家       亨利
在毕业典礼上用过的希伯来语
used during times of graduation.
Kadima  意思是前进
Kadima. It means, "Forward."
致前进
Forward.
-致前进  -致前进
- Forward. - Forward.
致前进
Forward.
-说得好  -谢谢
- Well said. - Thank you.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You good? - Ah, yeah.
在离开十四年之后
Stuff goes to your head after
会有一些东西跳进脑海
being away from it for 14 years.
肯定的  那么  好了
I bet. All right, well, look.
我在想  要不明天一早
I was thinking, what if, in the morning,
咱们俩去找间公寓一起住
the two of us started looking for an apartment for both of us,
其实爱瑞丝一直都在研究
and Iris has actually been doing some research on
怎么帮你拿回医生执照
how to get your medical license back
好让你再次开始行医
so you could start your practice up again,
或者如果你想
or, if you wanted,
也可以来尖端科研实验室和我们一起干
come work with us at S.T.A.R. Labs.
我不知道  我是说
I don't know. I mean--
怎么了  你没事吧
What's wrong? You okay?
没事  现在在开派对
Yeah, it's a party.
我们可以明天再谈这些
Come on, we can talk about all this tomorrow.
-谈什么  -巴里...
- Talk about what? - Barry...
你不打算留下来吗
Are you not planning on sticking around?
好吧
Okay.
好吧  你觉得
Okay, do you think--
你现在的所作的一切
can you be all that you are becoming...
有我在还能继续吗
With me here?
你是我唯一的家人
You're the only family that I have left.
实际不是这样  是不是
Well, that's not really true, is it?
难道在这房间里你没别的家人了吗
Don't you have another family in this room?
他们也需要你的帮助  巴里
They need your help too, Barry.
你需要我时  我会在你身边
When you need me, I will be here,
可现在中城不需要你
but right now, Central City doesn't need you
做亨利·艾伦的儿子
to be Henry Allen's son.
而是需要你成为闪电侠
It needs you to be the Flash.
我的孩子
My kid.
是超级英雄
The superhero.
我必须得走
I have to go.
我需要你告诉我可以走
I need you to tell me that it's okay.
好
Yeah.
你爸爸走得顺利吗
Your dad get off okay?
挺顺  我把他送到了车站
Yeah, I just dropped him at the station.
你没事吧
You good?
不知道  我
I don't know, I--
只是觉得每次胜利  我都输了什么
Just feels like every time I win, I still lose.
那么
Well...
也不算太坏
it's not bad.
是的  不算太坏
No, it's not bad.
-还挺酷的  -是真的很酷
- It's pretty cool. - It's real cool, come on!
猜猜怎么着
Hey, guess what?
我给你的战衣做了个小改进
I added a little upgrade to your suit.
和吉迪恩那张未来报纸上的
It's just like the one from the future newspaper
一模一样
Gideon showed us.
我在想
I was thinking, you know,
你不该再害怕未来了  对吧
you shouldn't fear the future anymore, right?
是的  未来比我们想像中要来得更快
No, and it'll be here faster than we think.
瞧瞧  我喜欢
Well, see, I like it.
搭配白色  就更加能凸显出闪电了
The lightning definitely pops more against the white.
还有  尖端科研实验室也比以前更安全
And S.T.A.R. Labs is now safer than ever.
安全和监控都增强了
Increased security and surveillance.
重新编码  双层防火墙  电子门锁
Re-coded, double firewalled, electronic lock sets.
不管是什么经过  我们都会知道
Nothing is getting through here without us knowing.
这样就没人能随便进出了
So people can't just waltz in and out of here.
没错
Exactly.
-不是吧  -站在那别动
- For real? - Stay where you are.
你是谁
Who are you?
你不认识我  但我认识你  巴里·艾伦
You don't know me, but I know you... Barry Allen.
再走一步  你就要见阎王老子了
Take one more step, it'll be the last step you take.
回答他的问题
The man asked you a question.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我叫杰伊·加里克
My name is Jay Garrick,
你的世界正面临着危机
And your world is in danger.